<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<addonCore>
  <label>Widgets Toolbox</label>
  <version>1.3.330</version>
  <type>Toolbox</type>
  <identifier>b0bebf59-856a-4068-9d9c-0ed8968ac9e6</identifier>
  <summary>Modular components and controls to efficiently develop advanced user interfaces in MATLAB.</summary>
  <description>Widgets Toolbox helps you efficiently develop advanced user interfaces in MATLAB. The toolbox provides additional UI controls and higher-level modules that implement common building blocks needed in MATLAB apps. Widgets combine existing control functionalities together into a larger, reusable, common functionality to accelerate development of graphical user interfaces. Existing users of GUI Layout Toolbox will find Widgets Toolbox pairs nicely with GUI Layout Toolbox. 

Example components are:
- A file selection control, consisting of a label, edit field, and browse button
- A listbox control combined with a label and a set of buttons for managing the list composition and ordering
- A tree control providing advanced functionalities like drag and drop, and checkbox nodes

Widgets Toolbox also provides
- Superclasses for a whole application, to provide and manage saving and loading session state to and from a MAT-file
- Dialog windows for several typical kinds of user selection (and more to come in future development)
- A logger, especially useful for complex or deployed apps, that will store application events/data (of a configurable severity level) to a log file and display them in the command window
- Framework for efficiently building your own widgets

Widgets Toolbox is most applicable to users who are writing hand code to develop complex, modular applications with hand code using object-oriented programming in MATLAB. This toolbox currently only supports traditional MATLAB figure windows (Java-based) and does not support web graphics used in uifigure containers or App Designer. Widgets may be added programmatically to a GUIDE-generated app, but they will not show up in the graphical GUIDE editor. 

It is recommended you install this as a toolbox to automatically set up the proper MATLAB and Java paths. If you install this manually, please review the installation directions in the Getting Started guide.

Planning a complex or business-critical app? MathWorks Consulting can advise you on design and architecture: https://www.mathworks.com/services/consulting/proven-solutions/software-development-with-matlab.html</description>
  <createdBy name="Robyn Jackey"/>
  <image>resources/screenshot.png</image>
</addonCore>
